Muawiya, Muhammad Alkali

901101, Bwari by Arab Contractors, Bwari Abuja Nigeria.

+2347060702020

muawiyamuhd@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-muawiya-alkali-16386b105

https://github.com/MM-Alkali

Summary

I am a highly motivated and hardworking individual with a creative mind, strong work ethic, and dedication to collaboration. My skills include exceptional problem-solving and numeracy abilities, effective communication and leadership, and efficient time management. As a proactive and driven engineer and leader with development experience, I have successfully designed and deployed software solutions for various business use cases, from conception to implementation. I excel in JavaScript development and have built software solutions for the healthcare, and entertainment industries, among others.

Technologies & Skills

Node.JS, Express.js, React.js | JavaScript, TypeScript | Docker | SQL, MongoDB | GraphQL, REST API | Git | Scrum | Microsoft Office | Teams, Slack, Jira & Trello | Individual Counselling | Psycho-Truama Healing

Experience

Decagon / Full Stack Engineer

January 2023 - Date, LAGOS

Developed and maintained web applications using web development concepts such as HTTP, REST, GraphQL, and MVC architecture. Built and managed databases using database management systems such as SQL and MongoDB. Implemented DevOps tools and methodologies such as Docker to improve application deployment and scalability. Utilized TypeScript to write clean, efficient, and well-documented code. Collaborated with cross-functional teams including product managers, designers, and other developers to build new features and enhance existing ones. Ensured the performance, security, and reliability of web applications by implementing best practices and testing strategies. Stayed up-to-date with emerging trends, technologies, and development practices in the web development field.

Techvibes International Ltd / User Experience & Marketing support

June 2019 - June 2020, ABUJA

Gathering and writing reports on product requirements for software; quality assessments of products through identifying, documenting problems and coordinating with the technical team to proffer solutions; monitoring and reporting users' reactions after launching software; supporting and training internal and external users.

Projects

FitMind

A health-tech app that connects clients with verified physical fitness experts and therapist.

Technologies: Express.js, Typescript, Sqlite, Sequelize, Docker, React

Link: https://fit-mind.onrender.com

MovieVerse

MovieVerse is a movie listing app where registered users can add, edit and delete movies with titles, images, price and brief description. It offers a user-friendly interface to manage the movie list easily.

Technologies: Express.js, Typescript, MongoDB, Mongoose, Docker, EJS

Link: https://movie-verse.onrender.com

Github Finder

A responsive Single Page Application which consumes data from the Github Graphql API

Technologies: GraphQL, HTML, CSS and Vanilla JavaScript

Link: https://mm-alkali.github.io/github-finder

Education

MODIBBO ADAMA UNIVERSITY

B.Tech Biochemistry
First Class (Hons)

DECEMBER 2012 - MAY 2019, YOLA

Certifications

EF SET English Proficiency Test Certificate
Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC)
Training on Bioinformatics
Introduction to Cyber Security
Docker for the absolute beginner
Accelerated Jobberman Soft SkillsTraining
YouWin Connect Capacity Building (Master Class Training)
Diploma in Data Processing